Anderson Parra de Paula

Software Engineer

ander.pp@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/anderparra



+49 1525 5783758

I believe that software enables people to be creative because it saves their time. I really enjoy building systems that bring value to stakeholders and users, always looking for opportunities to learn more and become a better professional. For me programming languages are tools that can fit in different ways for each solution. I always look forward to the best fit for every project.

I have over 10 years of industry experience in software engineering, having worked in many different types of systems with diverse sets of constraints and challenges, mainly based on the JVM (Java and Scala). I am also experienced in high-scale distributed systems and functional programming.

Experiences

Senior Software Engineer at LiveIntent

11/2017 - Present (Berlin, Germany)

Helping to build, maintain, scale and operate real-time systems dealing mostly with both HTTP and Event-driven based, but also with off-line/batch ones. I am working on a marketing and product analytics platform. It does three things: (1) Identifies users and tracks the way they engage with websites; (2) Enriches and stores collected data; (3) Uses big data tools to analyze that data and extracts business value.

Backend Engineer at SoundCloud

10/2015 - 10/2017 (Berlin, Germany)

Member of an agile team responsible for a system that provides accurate financial reporting to all monetization partners and automated calculation of royalty payments, in order to accommodate growth towards +10M monetized tracks in the platform and thousands of new partners.

Senior Software Engineer at Ericsson

10/2014 - 10/2015 (Athlone, Ireland)

Worked at Ericsson's SON Optimization Manager project that provides optimization of radio networks and multiple network elements and domains. This allowed the integration of multiple technologies (2G, 3G and 4G) and multiple vendors into a single optimization paradigm.

Principal Software Engineer at Amil

07/2011 - 10/2014 (São Paulo, Brazil)

Team leader of team responsible to develop and mainten a mission-critical high scale service available to all hospitals and clinics nationwide in order to comply with Brazilian government healthcare standards.

Senior Software Engineer at Amil

07/2009 - 07/2011 (São Paulo, Brazil)

Education

Big Data Specialization
University of Califorinia - Online
2016 - 2016

Master degree in Computer Science Federal University of São Carlos - Brazil 2012 - 2015

Focused on Distributed Systems and Data Replication. Dissertation titled "A Lightweight Reconfiguration Solution for Paxos".

Web Development Specialization

Federal University of São Carlos - Brazil 2009 - 2010

Bachelor degree in Computer Science University Anhembi Morumbi - Brazil

2005 - 2008

Skills

Distributed Systems

Data Replication

Event-driven architecture

Web Application

Web Services (REST / SOAP)

Microservices

Agile

Tools

Java	••••
Scala	••••
JavaScript	••••
Ruby	••••
Python	$\bullet \bullet \bullet \circ \circ$
Node.js	$\bullet \bullet \circ \circ$
HTML / CSS	

SQL	••••
Hadoop	••••
Spark	••••
Akka	••••
Docker	••••
Kubernetes	••••
AWS	••••